Guide to the Kane-Greenberg Collection of Progressive Proof Prints PR 242
New-York Historical Society
Kane-Greenberg collection of progressive proof prints
1890-1930
New-York Historical Society
PR 242
8.48 Linear feet (19 Boxes)
Access to Collection
Collection is open for research; access requires at least 24 hours advance notice.
Related Materials at The New-York Historical Society
The Kane-Greenberg Collection of Progressive Proof Prints spans the period from ca. 1890 to ca. 1930 and contains progressive chromolithograph proof books for cigar box labels. These proofs were used to check color quality. Brands from most of the major cigar companies of the time period are represented in the collection. The collection provides a wealth of material for studying the various American advertising themes and iconographic motifs used in the promotion and marketing of a single product. The books are arranged by the letter and number codes printed on them by Consolidated.
Scope and Contents Note
The Kane-Greenberg Collection of Progressive Proof Prints spans the period from ca. 1890 to ca. 1930 and contains progressive chromolithograph proof books for cigar box labels. These proofs were used to check color quality. Brands from most of the major cigar companies of the time period are represented in the collection. The collection provides a wealth of material for studying the various American advertising themes and iconographic motifs used in the promotion and marketing of a single product. The books are arranged by the letter and number codes printed on them by Consolidated.
Provenance
Gift of Raymond Kane, Stanley Greenberg, Neil Greenberg, and Morris Greenberg, 1983.
Arrangement Note
Proof books are filed alphabetically by letter, then by number. Books with no letter markings are filed after those with letters. Some proof books are filed in small portfolios, which are housed together, in numerical order. Proof books with no markings are filed at the end of the collection. Cigar brands are noted when apparent.
Organization of the Collection
This collection is organized into series:
Series I: "A" Numbers
Series II: "C" Numbers
Series III: "K" Numbers
Series IV: "M" Numbers"
Series V: Books With Numbers and No Letters
Series VI: Books With No Markings
Series VII: Portfolios
Series VIII: Oversize Materials
- Series I: "A" Numbers, 1
  - Muriel, 1917 Dec. 1 (Item A1130)
    General note
    See: Box 19
  - Muriel (Item A1262)
- Series II: "C" Numbers, 2
  - woman wearing star hat (Purple), undated (Box 1, Item C519)
  - Historians (Purple), 1927 Jul 14 (Box 1, Item C632)
  - John Hay (Purple), 1919 Jul 26 (Box 1, Item C668)
  - Louis James (Purple), undated (Box 1, Item C671)
  - Captain Larolle (Purple), undated (Box 1, Item C675)
  - La Melinda (Purple), 1923 Jul 30 (Box 1, Item C686)
  - Selinda (Purple), undated (Box 1, Item C690)
  - Royal Match (Purple), undated (Box 1, Item C693)
  - picture of girl in front of large leaf (Purple), undated (Box 1, Item C694)
  - Principe de Paz (Purple), undated (Box 1, Item C695)
  - Protocol (Purple), undated (Box 1, Item C722)
  - Prince Hal (Purple), undated (Box 1, Item C724)
  - woman with red flowers in hair (Purple), undated (Box 2, Item C725)
  - Parker House Bouquet (Purple), undated (Box 2, Item C728)
  - woman with green hat and dress (Purple), undated (Box 2, Item C752)
  - La Riqueza (Purple), 1902 Aug 15 (Box 2, Item C757)
  - Alida (Purple), undated (Box 2, Item C774)
  - Catriona (Purple), undated (Box 2, Item C775)
- Series III: "K" Numbers, 3
  - La Garcita (Purple), undated (Box 2, Item K42)
  - Henry W. Sage (Purple), undated (Box 2, Item K53)
  - Colorado Maid (Purple), undated (Box 2, Item K251)
  - Planta Bella (Purple), undated (Box 2, Item K253)
  - La Pretoria (Red), undated (Box 2, Item K268)
  - Opia (Purple), undated (Box 2, Item K283)
  - George Washington (Red), undated (Box 2, Item K294)
  - La Potencia (Red), undated (Box 2, Item K320)
  - Velasquez (Red), undated (Box 3, Item K330)
  - La Flor de Vega (Red), undated (Box 3, Item K334)
  - La Flor de Sheridan (Red), undated (Box 3, Item K339)
  - Colorado Maid (Red), undated (Box 3, Item K345)
  - Ruby Star (Red), undated (Box 3, Item K355)
  - Rose of Plymouth (Red), undated (Box 3, Item K356)
  - United Seal (Purple), undated (Box -, Item K363)
    See: Box 17
  - Walter Q. Gresham (Red), undated (Box 3, Item K393)
  - Tampa Girl (Red), undated (Box 3, Item K398)
  - Vintage (Red), undated (Box 3, Item K434)
  - La Pe-Ru-Na (Red), undated (Box 3, Item K465)
  - Pete Dailey (Red), undated (Box 3, Item K487)
  - El Prado (Red), undated (Box 3, Item K495)
  - Shenandoah (Red), undated (Box 3, Item K507)
  - Calvin S. Brice (Red), undated (Box 4, Item K510)
  - Haynie's Special (Red), 1916 Apr. 22 (Box 4, Item K515)
  - Fabrica de Tabacos Superioriores (Red), 1916 Apr. 22 (Box 4, Item K516)
  - Blanche Bates (Red), undated (Box 4, Item K524)
  - Nan Wilkes (Red), undated (Box 4, Item K533)
  - The Yates (Red), undated (Box 4, Item K543)
  - El Capitalista (Red), undated (Box 4, Item K550)
  - Superia (Purple), undated (Box 4, Item K585)
  - Samuel J. Tilden (Red), undated (Box 4, Item K593)
  - Robert Browning (Red), undated (Box 4, Item K599)
  - Robert Dunlap (Purple), undated (Box 4, Item K618)
  - Poke (Red), undated (Box 4, Item K623)
  - Maxine Elliott (Red), undated (Box 4, Item K627)
  - La Castalia (Red), undated (Box 4, Item K665)
  - La Unica (Red ), undated (Box 5, Item K962)
  - El Hernando (Red), undated (Box 5, Item K966)
  - Canoga (Purple), undated (Box 5, Item K976)
  - Dominor (Purple), undated (Box 5, Item K977)
  - Illinois Athletic Club (Purple), undated (Box 5, Item K996)
  - Joel Gay (Red), undated (Box 5, Item K1007)
  - Tom Palmer (Purple), undated (Box 5, Item K1011)
  - Bickel's Cigars (Purple), undated (Box -, Item K1029)
  - Don Planta (Purple), undated (Box 5, Item K1039)
  - Flower Girl (Purple), undated (Box 5, Item K1057)
  - Da Vinci (Purple), undated (Box 5, Item K1082)
  - La Siesta (Purple), undated (Box 5, Item K1407)
  - Taking (Purple), undated (Box 5, Item K1444)
  - Hands Up (Purple), undated (Box 5, Item K1569)
  - Dartmouth Club (Purple), undated (Box 5, Item K1749)
  - Morencia (Purple), 1929 Aug. 29 (Box 5, Item K1822)
  - Henry George (Purple), undated (Box -, Item K1872)
  - Prince Hamlet (Purple), undated (Box 6, Item K2059)
  - Espadilla ("New") (Purple), undated (Box 6, Item K2085)
  - John T. McCutcheon (unusable) (Purple), undated (Box 6, Item K2305)
  - Treasurer (Purple), undated (Box 6, Item K2319)
  - La Rosa Del Monte (Purple), undated (Box 6, Item K2323)
  - Puramia (unusable) (Purple), undated (Box 6, Item K2324)
  - Ansel Briggs (unusable) (Purple), undated (Box 6, Item K2326)
  - El Verso Junior (Black), undated (Box -, Item K2352)
  - Olena (unusable) (Purple), undated (Box 6, Item K2378)
  - V. Guerra Diaz & Co. (unusable) (Purple), undated (Box 6, Item K2393)
  - Walker Whiteside (unusable) (Purple), undated (Box 7, Item K2448)
  - Durand & Kasper (Purple), undated (Box 7, Item K2449)
  - Factory 100 (Purple), undated (Box 7, Item K2453)
  - Jerome Sykes (usuable) (Purple), undated (Box 7, Item K2535)
  - Governor Bagly (unusable) (Purple), undated (Box 7, Item K2572)
  - Flor de Narvez (Purple), undated (Box 7, Item K2580)
  - Ivora (partially unusable) (Purple), undated (Box 7, Item K2593)
  - La Visura (unusable) (Purple), undated (Box 7, Item K2603)
  - Garcia Monte (Purple), undated (Box 7, Item K2628)
  - Eugenio (Purple), undated (Box 7, Item K2630)
  - La Flor De Caravello (Purple), undated (Box 8, Item K2667)
  - Wireless (Purple), undated (Box 8, Item K2747)
  - Delhi (Purple), undated (Box 8, Item K3104)
  - Goetz (Purple), undated (Box 8, Item K3194)
  - Wedding Ring (Purple), undated (Box 8, Item K3233)
  - Twilight Club (Purple), undated (Box 8, Item K3259)
  - Temco (Purple), undated (Box 8, Item K3327)
  - Mrs. Gilbert (Purple), undated (Box 8, Item K3377)
  - Reynard (Purple), undated (Box 8, Item K3392)
  - El Distrito (Purple), undated (Box -, Item K3498)
  - Royal Tribute (Purple), undated (Box 8, Item K3505)
  - Elder (Purple), undated (Box 8, Item K3516)
  - La Estrela (Purple), undated (Box 8, Item K3516)
  - Ola Del Muro (Purple), undated (Box 8, Item K3637)
  - Decree (Purple), undated (Box 9, Item K3650)
  - Dolly Dollars (Purple), undated (Box 9, Item K4185)
  - Ed Howe (Purple), undated (Box 9, Item K4213)
  - Halo (Purple), undated (Box 9, Item K4273)
  - Turjo (Purple), undated (Box -, Item K4308)
  - Planter (Purple), undated (Box -, Item K4348)
  - Lady Lou (Purple), undated (Box 9, Item K4365)
  - La Flor de Wolota (Purple), undated (Box 9, Item K4413)
  - Campanella (Purple), undated (Box 9, Item K4429)
  - La Palina -- Original Stories, 3rd Prooving (Purple), 1928 Jun. (Box -, Item K4348)
  - La Palina -- Original Transfers (Purple) (Box -, Item K6751)
  - El Producto (Black), undated (Box -, Item K6880)
  - El Producto (Purple) (Box -, Item K6880)
  - La Palina (Purple), 1914 Nov. 21 (Box -, Item K6873)
  - Capulet (Black), undated (Box -, Item K7404)
  - Empress of Cuba (Black), undated (Box -, Item K7956)
  - Margate (Black), undated (Box -, Item K7973)
  - La Palina (Black), undated (Box -, Item K8009)
  - La Palina (Purple) (Box 9, Item K8009)
  - Aurelia (Black), undated (Box -, Item K8224)
  - Monroe Doctrine (Black), 1915 Apr. 26 (Box -, Item K9118)
- Series IV: "M" Numbers", 4
  - Tom Moore (Purple), undated (Box -, Item M766)
  - Tom Moore (Purple), 1919 Mar. 11 (Box 9, Item M766)
  - Tom Moore (Purple), 1901 Jul. 15 (Box 9, Item M766)
  - Chesterfield (Purple), 1915 Jun. 22 (Box 9, Item M772)
  - La Sedora (Purple), undated (Box 9, Item M1155)
  - Van Bibber Bouquet (Purple), undated (Box 9, Item M1175)
  - Van Bibber (Purple), undated (Box 9, Item M1832)
  - Van Dyck (Purple), undated (Box 10, Item M1988)
  - Van Dyck (Purple), 1919 Sep. 2 (Box 10, Item M1988)
  - W. M. Penn (Purple), undated (Box 10, Item M2272)
  - Gen. Arthur (Purple), 1917 Nov. 19 (Box 10, Item M2304)
  - Garcia Grande (Purple), 1908 Dec. 17 (Box -, Item M2373)
  - Robert Burns (Purple), undated (Box 10, Item M2816)
  - S-O-W-C-O (Purple), undated (Box 10, Item M3681)
  - General Arthur (Purple), undated (Box 10, Item M3916)
  - Tilford (Purple), undated (Box -, Item M4255)
  - Tilford (Purple), undated (Box -, Item M4255)
  - White Owl (Purple), 1921 Nov. 25 (Box 10, Item M4323)
  - The Harvester (Purple), 1924 Jan. 14 (Box -, Item M4916)
  - The Harvester (Purple), 1928 May 19 (Box -, Item M4916)
  - W.M. Penn (Black Impression Book) (Purple), 1906 Oct. 26 (Box 10, Item M5492)
  - Henry George (Purple), undated (Box -, Item M5553)
- Series V: Books With Numbers and No Letters, 5
  - Sam. Parr, undated (Box 10, Item 15)
  - Sunflower, undated (Box 10, Item 16)
  - El Producto, undated (Box 10, Item 26)
  - La Palina, undated (Box -, Item 27)
    See: Box 18
  - Fabrica de Tabacos Superioriores, 1915 Oct. 11 (Box 10, Item 49)
  - Two Orphans, undated (Box 10, Item 59)
  - Oniatta, undated (Box -, Item 60)
  - The Owl Brand, undated (Box -, Item 61)
  - Observa, undated (Box -, Item 63)
  - Ottina, undated (Box -, Item 64)
  - Observa, undated (Box 10, Item 65)
  - Ours, undated (Box 10, Item 66)
  - Vena De Oro, undated (Box 11, Item 67)
  - Byer's Perfectos, undated (Box -, Item 69)
  - La Encico, undated (Box 11, Item 71)
  - Austin, Nichols & Co./Whiphandle, undated (Box 11, Item 72)
  - Nappanee, undated (Box 11, Item 75)
  - La Nora, undated (Box 11, Item 77)
  - La Palma, undated (Box 11, Item 78)
  - Senor Pancho, undated (Box 11, Item 79)
  - Flor De Paley, undated (Box 11, Item 80)
  - Persus, undated (Box 11, Item 81)
  - Ain't They Lovely, undated (Box 11, Item 82)
  - Hamlet Y Ofelia, undated (Box -, Item 101)
  - Queen Caroline, undated (Box -, Item 152)
  - Leo Bancroft, undated (Box 11, Item 395)
  - Hooker's Plantation, undated (Box 11, Item 432)
  - La Renola, undated (Box 11, Item 539)
  - Flor de Gadiz, undated (Box -, Item 543)
  - [man in military dress], undated (Box 12, Item 567)
  - First Consul, undated (Box 12, Item 580)
  - A. Lincoln, undated (Box 12, Item 585)
  - Tropical Charms, undated (Box -, Item 593)
  - Siesta, undated (Box 12, Item 598)
  - Walz's White Slave, 1913 May 19 (Box 12, Item 604)
  - El Producto, undated (Box 12, Item 630)
  - El Generallo, undated (Box 12, Item 657)
  - The Harvester, undated (Box -, Item 669)
  - El Colonial, undated (Box -, Item 673)
  - [woman in gold crown], undated (Box 12, Item 677)
  - Eduard Strauss, undated (Box 12, Item 678)
  - [man in red hat, blue frock], undated (Box 12, Item 686)
  - Two Sisters, undated (Box 12, Item 714)
  - La Realidad, 1915 Dec. 15 (Box 12, Item 752)
  - La Versada, 1923 May 17 (Box 12, Item 761)
  - El Cabinet, undated (Box 12, Item 771)
  - [man and woman playing chess], undated (Box 12, Item 809)
  - Lord Dunraven, undated (Box 13, Item 821)
  - La Camelia, undated (Box 13, Item 828)
  - Raphael, undated (Box 13, Item 870)
  - Cavalier, undated (Box 13, Item 915)
  - La Radiasa, undated (Box 13, Item 941)
  - Bachelor's Club, undated (Box 13, Item 1042)
  - Snow Bird, 1917 Nov. 1 (Box 13, Item 1049)
  - Van Dyke Operas, undated (Box 13, Item 1096)
  - Fabrica de Tabacos De La Vuelta Abajo, undated (Box 13, Item 1263)
  - Morey's Par Excellence, undated (Box 13, Item 1420)
  - La Fayette, 1919 Aug. 16 (Box 13, Item 1717)
  - De Soto Challenge, 1927 Nov. 25 (Box 13, Item 2274)
  - First Cabinet, 1935 Jan. 30 (Box -, Item 3531)
  - Bouquet de Eduardo H. Gato, undated (Box -, Item 5618)
  - La Flor de Garcia Vega, undated (Box -, Item 5796)
- Series VI: Books With No Markings, 6
  - El Destino, undated (Box 14)
  - La Flor De Magnolia, undated (Box 14)
  - Magistrate, 1899 May (Box 14)
  - Majestic, undated (Box 14)
  - La Palina, undated
  - Royal Turban, undated (Box 14)
  - El Tido, undated (Box 14)
  - La Toscana, undated
- Series VII: Portfolios, 7
  - John Burns, 1908 Jun. 1 (Box 14, Item 66)
  - Custom House, 1908 Mar. 10 (Box 14, Item 83)
  - Franz Hals, 1908 Jun. 8 (Box 14, Item 95)
  - Finck's Commerce, 1913 Mar. 18 (Box 14, Item 163)
  - New Post Office, 1918 Jun. 6 (Box 14, Item 175)
  - Good Luck, 1908 Mar. 10 (Box 14, Item 204S)
  - Royal Violet, 1908 Sep. 14 (Box 14, Item 287)
  - The Pony, 1910 Mar. 25 (Box 14, Item 297)
  - Our Progress, 1899 Oct. (Box 14, Item 298S)
  - La Reala, 1908 Mar. 10 (Box 14, Item 314S)
  - San Tula, 1908 Mar. 17 (Box 14, Item 315)
  - Royal Sterling, 1908 Mar. 10 (Box 14, Item 319S)
  - Lone Trail, 1913 Jun. 27 (Box 14, Item 326S)
  - White Rose (F.J. Schneckenberger), 1908 Mar. 17 (Box 14, Item 355)
  - Nobleza, 1909 May 10 (Box 14, Item 356S)
  - Lavinda, 1908 Sep. 18 (Box 14, Item 359)
  - Lord Stovall, 1910 Jan. 21 (Box 14, Item 364)
  - Francisco Goya, 1912 Dec. 4 (Box 14, Item 407)
  - Medberry, 1908 Mar. 11 (Box 14, Item 412)
  - Turf Kings, 1908 Mar. 17 (Box 14, Item 424)
  - Governor Dole, 1908 Mar. 17 (Box 14, Item 427)
  - Lady Carlin, 1908 Sep. 28 (Box 14, Item 432)
  - Frances Burnett, 1908 Mar. 17 (Box 15, Item 435)
  - Peacock, 1908 Mar. 17 (Box 15, Item 446)
  - Youess, 1908 Mar. 17 (Box 15, Item 454)
  - La Zinda, undated (Box 15, Item 461)
  - Sydney Smith, 1908 Mar. 17 (Box 15, Item 462)
  - La Premonette, 1908 Mar. 17 (Box 15, Item 543)
  - Flor de Gounod, 1908 Mar. 17 (Box 15, Item 546)
  - Texas Fine Million Club, 1908 Mar. 17 (Box 15, Item 562)
  - Magistrate, 1908 Mar. 31 (Box 15, Item 581)
  - Suzanne, 1908 Mar. 31 (Box 15, Item 595)
  - El Sobano, 1908 Mar. 14 (Box 15, Item 597)
  - Lily Belle, 1908 Mar. 31 (Box 15, Item 603)
  - Mi Ziola, 1908 Mar. 31 (Box 15, Item 667)
  - Commercio del Mundo, 1908 Mar. 31 (Box 15, Item 669)
  - Mundane, 1910 Aug. 15 (Box 15, Item 670)
  - Newark Armory, 1908 Mar. 31 (Box 15, Item 677)
  - La Serada, 1908 Mar. 31 (Box 15, Item 691)
  - Saeger's 43, 1908 Mar. 31 (Box 15, Item 713)
  - Battenberg (A.M. Tobias & Co.), 1909 Aug. 23 (Box 15, Item 715)
  - Cheerful, 1908 Apr. 1 (Box 15, Item 717)
  - Jefferson Seal, 1908 Apr. 1 (Box 15, Item 728)
  - Kyana, 1908 Apr. 1 (Box 15, Item 734)
  - Dock Fox, 1908 Apr. 1 (Box 15, Item 743)
  - La Introduccion, 1908 Apr. 1 (Box 15, Item 744)
  - El Manton, 1909 Aug. 23 (Box 15, Item 752)
  - The Old Green, 1908 Apr. 1 (Box 15, Item 755)
  - Colonel McComas, 1908 Apr. 1 (Box 15, Item 767)
  - Delight, 1908 Apr. 1 (Box 16, Item 770)
  - Right Royal, 1908 Apr. 1 (Box 16, Item 771)
  - Rose-Dale, 1908 Apr. 1 (Box 16, Item 782)
  - Horace Mann, 1908 Apr. 1 (Box 16, Item 788)
  - Our Limit, 1913 Jan. (Box 16, Item 815)
  - Iristol, 1908 Apr 3 (Box 16, Item 818)
  - Lotus Club, 1908 Apr 3 (Box 16, Item 823)
  - Crown Jewels, 1908 Apr 3 (Box 16, Item 830)
  - Toscanelli, 1908 Apr 3 (Box 16, Item 851)
  - Swisses, 1908 May 13 (Box 16, Item 1861)
  - Blue Bonnet, 1908 May 13 (Box 16, Item 1872)
  - La Crema de Cuba, 1908 May 13 (Box 16, Item 1882)
  - [Indian Head], 1908 May 13 (Box 16, Item 1900)
  - Tampa Royal, 1908 Dec. 30 (Box 16, Item 1929)
  - Red King, 1908 Nov. 20 (Box 16, Item 1953)
  - Brandavana, 1911 Mar. (Box 16, Item 2152)
- Series VIII: Oversize Materials, 8
  - Subseries VIII.1: From "A" Numbers, 1
    - Muriel, 1917 Dec. 1 (Box 19, Item A1130)
    - Muriel (Box 19, Item A1262)
  - Subseries VIII.2: From "K" Numbers, 2
    - United Seal, undated (Box 17, Item K363)
    - El Verso Junior, undated (Box 17, Item K2352)
    - El Distrito, undated (Box 17, Item K3498)
    - Turjo, undated (Box 17, Item K4308)
    - Planter, undated (Box 17, Item K4348)
    - El Producto, undated (Box 17, Item K6880)
    - Empress of Cuba, undated (Box 17, Item K7956)
    - Margate, undated (Box 17, Item K7973)
    - La Palina, undated (Box 17, Item K8009)
    - Aurelia, undated (Box 17, Item K8224)
    - Monroe Doctrine, 1915 Apr. 26 (Box 17, Item K9118)
    - Bickel's Cigars, undated (Box 19, Item K1029)
    - Da Vinci, undated (Box 19, Item K1082)
    - La Siesta, undated (Box 19, Item K1407)
    - Henry George, undated (Box 19, Item K1872)
    - La Palina, 1928 Jun. (Box 19, Item K6751)
    - La Palina, 1914 Nov. 21 (Box 19, Item K6873)
  - Subseries VIII.3: From "M" Numbers, 3
    - Garcia Grande, 1908 Dec. 17 (Box 17, Item M2373)
    - Tilford, undated (Box 17, Item M4255)
    - The Harvester, 1924 Jan. 14 (Box 17, Item M4916)
    - The Harvester, 1928 May 19 (Box 17, Item M4916)
    - Tom Moore, undated (Box 19, Item M766)
    - Tilford, undated (Box 19, Item M4255)
    - Henry George, undated (Box 19, Item M5553)
  - Subseries VIII.4: From Books With Numbers and No Letters, 4
    - La Palina, undated (Box 18, Item 27)
    - Oniatta, undated (Box 18, Item 60)
    - The Owl Brand, undated (Box 18, Item 61)
    - Observa, undated (Box 18, Item 63)
    - Ottina, undated (Box 18, Item 64)
    - Byer's Perfectos, undated (Box 18, Item 69)
    - Hamlet Y Ofelia, undated (Box 18, Item 101)
    - Queen Caroline, undated (Box 18, Item 152)
    - Flor de Gadiz, undated (Box 18, Item 543)
    - Tropical Charms, undated (Box 18, Item 593)
    - The Harvester, undated (Box 18, Item 669)
    - El Colonial, undated (Box 18, Item 673)
    - First Cabinet, 1935 Jan. 30 (Box 19, Item 3531)
    - Bouquet de Eduardo H. Gato, undated (Box 19, Item 5681)
    - La Flor de Garcia Vega, undated (Box 19, Item 5796)
  - Subseries VIII.5: From Books With No Markings, 5
    - La Palina, undated (Box 19)
    - La Toscana, undated (Box 19)